Here, the Markov Assumption will help us again.
这里 马尔可夫假设又派上用场了
Since you assume you're now this tagged x_t,
因为你假设你现在知道状态 Xt
it doesn't really matter what the car observes and how it moves before x_t.
那么车辆的观察结果以及在 Xt 之前的移动如何都不重要了
These values were already used to estimate x_t,
这些值已经用来估算 Xt 了
and that t will not benefit from these values.
而且这些值对 t 没有价值
This means, we assume that that t is independent
这意味着 我们假设 t 独立于
of all previous observations and the controls.
之前的所有观察和控制
Again, this is an example of the use of the Markov Assumption.
同样地 这个例子也使用了马尔可夫假设
And I can simplify our posterior distribution to p of z_t,
我可以把我们的先验分布简化为 p(zt)
only depends on x_t and the map.
仅依赖于 Xt 和地图
Let's take a closer look to the observation model.
我们再仔细看看观察模型
Do you remember that that t is or could be a vector of multiple observations?
你是否记得 这个 t 是或者可能是多次观察的向量？
This means, we rewrite the observation model in this way.
这意味着 我们可以用这种方式重写观察模型
Now we assume that the noise behavior of the individual range values
现在 我们假设单个距离值 zt 1 到 zt k 的噪音行为
z_t_1 to z_t_K is independent.
是相互独立的
This also means that all observations are independent.
这也意味着所有观察都是相互独立的
And it allows us to represent a observation model as a product
因此 我们能够把观察模型表示为
of the individual probability distributions of each single range measurement.
每个单个距离测量值的单独概率分布的乘积
Now the question is,
现在 问题是
how we should define the observation model forcing a range measurement?
我们如何定义单个距离测量值的观察模型？
In general, there are a lot of different observation models,
一般来说 有很多不同的观察模型
because we have a lot of different sensors like lidars,
因为我们有很多不同传感器 比如激光雷达
cameras, radars, or ultransonic sensors.
摄像头、雷达或超声传感器
And each sensor has a specific noise behavior and performance.
而且每个传感器都有特定的噪音行为和表现
The observation model also depends on the type of the map.
观察模型还依赖于地图类型
You can have dense 2D or 3D grid maps or sparse feature-based maps.
你可以使用密集的二维或三维网格地图 或基于特征的稀疏地图
In our 1D example,
在我们的一维案例中
we assume that our sensor measures that
我们假设传感器测量了
range to the n closest objects in driving direction.
距离驾驶方向上最近的 n 个对象的距离
As shown on the right side,
如右侧所示
the car measures 90 meters to the first and 37 meters to the second object.
汽车测量了 19 米 探测到第一个对象 然后 又测量了 37 米 探测到第二个对象
As stated before, the objects represents the landmarks in our map.
前面说过 对象代表地图上的地标
Here, we assume the observation noise can be modeled
这里 我们假设观察噪音可以建模为
as a Gaussian with a standard deviation of one meter.
高斯分布 标准差为 1 米
We also assume that our sensor can measure in a range between zero and 100 meters.
我们还假设 传感器可以测量的范围是 0 到 100 米
To implement observation model,
要实现观察模型
you use a given x_t and the given map to estimate so called pseudo ranges.
你使用给定的状态 Xt 和给定的地图来估算所谓的伪距离
These pseudo ranges represent a true range values and as assumption,
这些伪距离代表了真实的距离值 其假设条件为
your car would stand at the specific position,
车辆在地图上的具体位置
x_t, and the map.
是 Xt
For example, assume your car is standing here at position 20,
例如 假设你的车辆在位置 20 这里
and would observe five meters to the first,
并且首先观察到 5 米
11 meters to the second,
然后观察到 11 米
39 metres to the third,
接着是 39 米
and 57 meters to the last landmark.
最后是第 57 米 观察到最后一个地标
Compared to the real observations,
和真正的观察相比
this position seems very unlikely, right?
这个位置看起来很不可能 对吗？
So observation would rather fit to a position around 40.
因此 观察更接近在位置 40 的这个地方
Based on this example,
根据这个例子
the observation model for a single range measurement is
单个距离测量的观察模型
defined by the probability of the following normal distribution,
可以根据下列正态分布确定
defined by the mean z-star_t_K and our sigma.
该正态分布由 Z 星 tk 和 sigma确定
These insights allows you to implement observation model in C++.
深入了解之后 你就能够在 C++ 中实现观察模型了
But before you go back to the coding part,
但在你开始编程之前
I would like to finalize the theory of the base localization further.
先和我一起学完基本定位滤波器理论的最后部分